Inventory of the Dieter Zahn collection
Hoover Institution Archives
Dieter Zahn collection
1959-1994
2011C41
Zahn, Dieter
5 manuscript boxes (2 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Election campaign literature and other printed political ephemera, mainly from Germany.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2006.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in Socrates is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Scope and Content of Collection
The Dieter Zahn collection consists of political pamphlets, brochures, and other ephemera collected by Zahn, a German journalist, who gathered much of this material during his international travels between 1979 and the time of his death in 1999.
The collection was acquired by the Hoover Institution Library and Archives from his son, Ralph, in 2006. In addition to the four boxes of political ephemera, the collection included over 1,000 political posters, which were added to the Poster Collection of the Hoover Institution Archives, but which have labels identifying their provenance.
The five boxes of pamphlets, brochures and ephemera are arranged by size, then by country of origin, and in some cases, by political party or topic within the country. Many of the European materials, in particular, were produced during election campaigns for the European Parliament from 1979 onward, but other topics and campaigns are included as well. Materials include flyers, leaflets, sample ballots, campaign newspapers, magazines, newspaper advertisements, booklets, election manifestos, and window posters.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Elections--Germany
Collection Contents
- Political ephemera, 1959-1994 (Box 1-5)
  Pamphlets, flyers, leaflets, window posters, and other related ephemera, arranged alphabetically by country of origin, and then within each country, by political party or organization.
  - Austria
    - SPÖ (Sozialistische Partei Österreichs)
      - 1983 (Folder 1: 1)
      - 1986 (Folder 1: 2)
  - Belgium (includes SP, PVV-ELD, Vlaamse Christen-Democraten), 1984-1989 (Folder 1: 3)
  - Brazil (Partido Democrática Social), 1982 (Folder 1: 4)
  - Canada (Communist Party of Canada), 1979-1980 (Folder 1: 5)
  - Denmark (Socialdemokraterne, Centrum-Demokraterne), 1984-1989 (Folder 1: 6)
  - European Parliament political groups
    - ELDR (European Liberal Democratic and Reform Party), 1979-1989 (Folder 1: 7)
    - European People's Party, 1984 (Folder 1: 8)
  - Finland (Centre Party), 1982 and undated (Folder 1: 9)
  - France
    - Centre des Démocrates Sociaux, 1984 (Folder 1: 10)
    - Centre National des Indépendants et Paysans, 1984-1986 (Folder 1: 10)
    - Front National, 1986 and undated (Folder 1: 10)
    - Parti Communiste Français, 1986 (Folder 1: 10)
    - Parti Radical Socialiste, 1973-1979 (Folder 1: 10)
    - Parti Socialiste, 1986 and undated (Folder 1: 10)
  - Germany
    - Bayern Partei, 1989 (Folder 1: 11)
    - CDU (Christlich-Demokratische Union)
      - General, 1972-1988 (Folder 1: 12)
      - European Parliament election, 1984 (Folder 2: 1)
      - Hamburg election, 1982 (Folder 2: 2)
      - Nordrhein-Westfalen, 1985 (Folder 2: 3)
      - Rheinland-Pfalz, 1982-1988 (Folder 2: 4)
    - CSU (Christlich-Soziale Union), 1973-1978 (Folder 2: 5)
    - Christliche Mitte, 1989 and undated (Folder 2: 6)
    - Deutsche Volks Union (DVU), 1989 (Folder 2: 7)
    - Europa Partei (EFP), 1984 (Folder 2: 8)
    - FDP (Frei Demokratische Partei / Die Liberalen), 1971-1987 (Folder 2: 9)
    - Graue Panther (Die Grauen), 1994 (Folder 2: 10)
    - Green Party (Die Grünen), and predecessor movements, 1978-1994 (Folder 2: 11)
    - MLPD (Marxistisch-Leninistisch Partei Deutschlands), 1989 (Folder 2: 12)
    - NPD (Nationaldemokratische Partei Deutschlands, undated, circa 1970s (Folder 2: 13)
    - Die Republikaner, 1993-1994 (Folder 2: 14)
    - SPD (Sozialdemokratische Partei Deutschlands)
      - General, 1962-1983 (Folder 3: 1)
      - Party programs, 1959-1979 (Folder 3: 2)
      - Saarland election, 1985 (Folder 3: 3)
    - Various parties and groups, 1979-1994 (Folder 3: 4)
    - Elections, Federal Republic of Germany
      - 1979, European Parliament (Folder 3: 5)
      - 1990, Baden-Württemberg (Folder 3: 6)
      - 1994, Baden-Württemberg (Folder 3: 7)
    - Elections, German Democratic Republic, 1990 (March 18) (Folder 3: 8)
    - General topics
      - Berlin, 1961-1963 (Folder 3: 9)
      - Constitution (Grundgesetz), 1961-1976 (Folder 3: 10)
      - Government, 1964-1992 (Folder 4: 1)
  - Greece, 1989 and undated (Folder 4: 2)
  - Iraq (publication of embassy in Germany), 1982 (Folder 4: 3)
  - Ireland (Labour Party), 1984 (Folder 4: 4)
  - Italy
    - Partito Liberale Italiano (PLI), 1983 and undated (Folder 4: 5)
    - Partito Radicale, 1992 (Folder 4: 6)
    - Partito Socialista Italia (PSI), 1987 (Folder 4: 7)
    - Various, 1984-1987 (Folder 4: 8)
  - Libya (pictures of Moammar Gadhafi), undated (Folder 4: 9)
  - Luxembourg, 1989 and undated (Folder 4: 10)
  - Mexico (Partido Acción Nacional), 1973-1988 (Folder 4: 11)
  - Netherlands, 1989 and undated (Folder 4: 12)
  - Portugal (Partido Socialista), 1983 (Folder 4: 13)
  - South Africa (National Party), 1981 (Folder 4: 14)
  - Sweden (Folkpartiet, Kristen Demokratisk Samling, Kristliga Förbundet), 1983-1985 and undated (Folder 4: 15)
  - Turkey (CHP, MHP), 1977-1979 and undated (Folder 4: 16)
  - United Kingdom (Labour, Liberal-SDP Alliance, Green Party, Scottish National Party, Liberal Democrats, SDLP), 1984-1992 (Folder 4: 17)
  - United States (Republican Party, Socialist Labor Party), 1980 and undated (Folder 4: 18)
  - Oversize material: Includes large-format newspapers, window posters, banners, and decals from Luxembourg, Netherlands, South Africa, and the United Kingdom (Wales, Northern Ireland) (Folder 5)